Guide to the National Association of Science Writers and Council for the Advancement of Science Writing records, 1934-2016
National Association of Science Writers and Council for the Advancement of Science Writing records, 1934-2016
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
National Association of Science Writers and Council for the Advancement of Science Writing records, 1934-2016.
4448
National Association of Science Writers.
29 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the National Association of Science Writers and the Council for the Advancement of Science Writing include correspondence, membership records, financial records, administrative material, working papers for seminars and workshops, samples of science writing, papers and theses, published reports, and video and audiocassettes. Correspondents include Earl Ubell, William J. Cromie, Pierre Fraley, Philip M. Boffey, Jane Stafford, and Herbert L. Nichols. Organizations mentioned include the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the Ford Foundation.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The National Association of Science Writers (NASW) is a professional society, established in 1934, serving science journalists and public information specialists. The Council for the Advancement of Science Writing (CASW), which was created in 1960, is a non-profit organization that sponsors various activities intended to improve the quality and quantity of information about science that reaches the public.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the National Association of Science Writers and the Council for the Advancement of Science Writing include correspondence, membership records, financial records, administrative material, working papers for seminars and workshops, samples of science writing, papers and theses, published reports, and video and audiocassettes. Correspondents include Earl Ubell, William J. Cromie, Pierre Fraley, Philip M. Boffey, Jane Stafford, and Herbert L. Nichols. Organizations mentioned include the American Association for the Advancement of Science and the Ford Foundation.
Also, oral history interview with Jane Stafford by Bruce Lewenstein, 1987.
SUBJECTS
Names:
National Association of Science Writers.; Boffey, Philip M.; Cromie, William J.; Fraley, Pierre.; Lewenstein, Bruce V.,; Nichols, Herbert L.(Herbert Lownds), 1908-; Stafford, Jane.; Ubell, Earl.; American Association for the Advancement of Science.; Council for the Advancement of Science Writing.; Council for the Advancement of Science Writing.; Ford Foundation.; National Association of Science Writers.
Subjects:
Science news--United States.; Communication in science--United States.; Journalism--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audio tapes.; Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a copy of the printed finding aid. PDF file.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by the above guide.
- Publications and unpublished articles, 19-19 (Box 32)
- Conference files, 1984-1999 (Box 32)
- Awards files, 1989-2000 (Box 32)
- Awards files, 1993-2000 (Box 33)
- Fellowship files: Haseltine, 1987-1990 (Box 33)
- Fellowship files: Kellogg, 1990-1996 (Box 33)
- Fellowship files: NASW-Duke University, 1985 (Box 33)
- Fellowship files: Ullman, 1983 (Box 33)
- Press release, 1985 (Box 33)
- Jane Stafford Oral History, 1989 (Box 33)
- Press Room Book, 1992 (Box 33)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-1996 (Box 33)
- External correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 33)
- Poster from University of California, Santa Cruz (Box 33)
- NASW LOGO Designs (Box 33)
- Letterhead and blank certificates (Box 33)
- American Chemical Society/Victor Cohn’s Presentation/October 15, 1999 (videotape) (Box 33)
- General Meeting/Excom/ New Orleans, 2/17/1990; The New York Academy of Sciences, Panels 1 & 2, 9/27/1994; The Osgood File/Network Access Project IV, 1998, 1990, 1994, 1998 (Box 33)
- Science Writing Survey, 1977-1992 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- CASW Report and correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Washington Independent Writers: directory of members, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Membership rosters and miscellaneous, 1982-2004 (Box 34, Folder 4)
- NASW directories of members, 1982, 1986-1990, 1992-1993 (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Agenda, 1984-1986 (Box 34, Folder 6)
- CASW meeting minutes, 1986-1996 (Box 34, Folder 7)
- CASW - Traveling Fellowship Committee, 1987-1992 (Box 34, Folder 8)
- Science Writing Survey, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 9)
- New Horizons in Science proposal file copy, 1988-1990 (Box 34, Folder 10)
- NSF correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 34, Folder 11)
- Agricultural Travel Fellowship Program, 1990-1991 (Box 34, Folder 12)
- Kellogg/report final letter/budget, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 13)
- CASW Agriculture Fellowships - applicants, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 14)
- Society of Environmental Journalists (SEJ): membership directories, 1991, 1992, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 15)
- Agriculture articles and publicity, 1991-1995 (Box 34, Folder 16)
- CASW Annual Briefing: New Horizons in Science, 1991-2004 (Box 34, Folder 17)
- CASW Bio's '92 election, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 18)
- Kellogg - Africa, 1994-1995 (Box 34, Folder 19)
- NASW Membership Directories, 1994, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 20)
- Mass Media Fellows: Directory, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 21)
- SEJ: membership directories, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 22)
- CASW programs and activities, 1997-1999 (Box 34, Folder 23)
- SEJ: membership directories, 1997-1999 (Box 34, Folder 24)
- NASW membership directories and resource guides, 1999-2001 (Box 34, Folder 25)
- Science-in-Society journalism awards, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 26)
- NASW membership directory and resource guide, 2001 (Box 34, Folder 27)
- NOVA/Secrets, Lies, and Atomic Spies, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 28)
- ScienceWriters newsletter volume 52, 2002-2003 (Box 34, Folder 29)
- NASW membership directory and resource guide, 2003 (Box 34, Folder 30)
- ScienceWriters newsletter volume 53, 2003-2004 (Box 34, Folder 31)
- NASW membership directory and resource guide, 2004 (Box 34, Folder 32)
- ScienceWriters newsletter volume 54, 2004-2005 (Box 34, Folder 33)
- ScienceWriters, 2013-2016 (Box 34, Folder 34)
- Brochures from NASW events, 2013-2014 (Box 34, Folder 35)
- CASW awards, 2000-2004 (Box 35, Folder 1)
- News & Numbers, Victor Cohn, 1989, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 2)
- Victor Cohn prize: nomination Shannon Brownlee, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 3)
- Victor Cohn prize: nomination Christine Gorman, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 4)
- Victor Cohn prize: nomination Daniel Haney, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Victor Cohn prize: nomination Michelle Trudeau, 2 CD-ROM, 2004; 420 (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
- Victor Cohn prize: nomination Jeff Wheelwright, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 8)
- Evolution t.v. series: "Darwin's Dangerous Idea" (drama script), 2001 (Box 35, Folder 9)
- Engineering and Life, 2 CD-ROM, 2002; 421 (Box 35, Folder 10)
- Bloodlines: Technology Hits Home, CD-ROM, 2003; 422 (Box 35, Folder 11-12)
- Bloodlines: Technology Hits Home, videotape, 2003 (Box 35)
- Building a New Child.. .. and Free to Be Me, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 13)
- Science in Society journalism awards, 2000, 2002-2004 (Box 35, Folder 14-18)
- NASW Roster of Members, 1982-1983, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 19)
- NASW membership directory, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 20)
- NASW membership directory, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 21)
- NASW membership directory, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 22)
- Evolution t.v. series: 7 videotapes [7 programs], 2001 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 1: Darwin's Dangerous Idea, V-1359 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 2: Great Transformations, V-1360 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 3: Extinction, V-1361 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 4: Evolutionary Arms Race, V-1362 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 5: Why Sex?, V-1363 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 6: The Mind's Big Bang, V-1364 (Box 35)
  - Evolution shows 7: What About God?, V-1365 (Box 35)
- Bloodlines: Technology Hits Home, 2003; V-1366 (Box 35)
- NASW workshops (12 audio cassettes), 2001; 8270a-8281a (Box 35)
- Directory of Science Communication Courses and Programs in U.S.A., 1993 (Box 35, Folder 23)
- Victor Cohn Award nomination: Laurie Garrett, 2000 (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Victor Cohn Award nomination: Dan Fagin, 2002 (Box 36, Folder 2)
- NASW newsletter, 2015 (Box 36, Folder 3)
- NASW Newsletters, 2005-2006 (Box 37, Folder 1)
- National Association of Science Writers, Inc. (NASW) Membership Directory, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 2)
- NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 3)
- NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners: Beth Whitehouse, “The Match”, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 4)
- NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners: Stephen Lyons and Llewellyn M. Smith, Forgotten Genius. DVD, 2007; 483 (Box 37, Folder 5)
- NASW Science in Society Journalism Award Winners: Alison Richard and David Malakoff, Climate Connections: How People Change Climate, How Climate Changes People. 2 CDs, 2007; 423, 425 (Box 37, Folder 6)
- Membership lists and directories, 1977, 1979, 1982-1983, 1988, 1991, 1993-1995, 1997-2007, 1977-2007 (Box 38, Folder 1-15)
- Science in Journalism leaflets, 1979, 1985-1990, l992-1993, 1995-2002, 2004-2007, 1979-2007 (Box 38, Folder 16)
- Membership recruitment leaflets, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 16)
- Membership cards, 2007-2008 (Box 38, Folder 16)
- A guide to careers in science writing, [1998] (Box 38, Folder 17)
- "Engineering & Life" [CD] (Box 38, Folder 17)
- Science journalism schools/courses, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 17)
- Science Writers Awards, 1990, 1992, 1993, 2005, 1990-2005 (Box 38, Folder 18)
- Award winner, 2003: "Bloodlines" [V-1099 and CD-315] (Box 38, Folder 19)
- A Field Guide for Science Writers, Deborah Blum, Mary Knudson, and Robin Morantz Henig (Box 38, Folder 19)
- Communicating Science News, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 19)
- "Physics Today" March 1979 (Box 38, Folder 20)
- NASW Newsletter, 1979-2006 (Box 38, Folder 21-29)
- Tribute to Mosaic, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 30)
- Science-in-Society Journalism Awards, 1987-2005 (Box 38, Folder 31-34)
- Conference session audio tapes (first copies), 1998-2001 (Box 39)
- Conference session audio tapes (use copies) [not complete], 1998-2001 (Box 40)
- NASW membership list (2), 1978 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- The Writer magazine essay contest forms (Box 41, Folder 1)
- Ballot, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 1)
- NASW certificates (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Council of Writers Organization [now defunct] (Box 41, Folder 3)
- NASW financial statements, 1989-2003 (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
- CASW Board of Directors, 1984-1998 (Box 41, Folder 6)
- CASW Board of Directors, 1999-2009 (Box 41, Folder 7)
- CASW Annual Reports, 1997-2009 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- New Horizons, 1996, 2003-2007 (Box 41, Folder 9)
- New Horizons in Science, 2008-2010 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Victor Cohn Award, 2000-2010 (Box 41, Folder 11)
- Victor Cohn Award (Box 41, Folder 12)
- Victor Cohn (Box 41, Folder 13)
- 50th Anniversary (Box 41, Folder 14)
- CASW Miscellaneous (Box 41, Folder 15)
- NASW Miscellaneous (Box 41, Folder 16)
- CASW 50th Token of Appreciation to Guests and Speakers (Box 41)
- Additional files (Box 42)
- Additional files (Box 43)